# Ruijia "Regina" Cheng

#### **Human Centered Research Scientist & UX Researcher**

regina.cheng0616@gmail.com | https://reginachangzhou.github.io

Ph.D. in Human-computer interaction (HCI). 6+ years of experience in qualitative and quantitative research on LLM & ML tools, programming, creativity & writing platforms, online communities, and education technology.

*Key Skills* Qualitative Research: interview, ethnography, usability testing, design probe, grounded theory, design workshops, thematic analysis, literature review | Quantitative Research: survey, A/B testing, experiment design, statistical modeling, inferential statistics, psychophysics | Programming: Python, R, SQL, MATLAB, JavaScript, web development (React, Node.js), machine learning (PyTorch), Unity | Design: Photoshop, Figma, Illustration, Blender

## **Selected Professional Experiences**

#### Apple, AI/ML Resident, Human Centered Machine Learning

07/2023 to present

- Led and conducted research on applications of LLM and machine learning in creativity and developer tools.
- Designed and conducted human centered research around AI systems; designed and build AI research prototypes.
- Presented to VP-level directors and in company-wide summits. Published in broader academic communities.

#### University of Washington, Graduate Researcher, HCI

09/2018 to 06/2023

- Led 10+ formative and evaluative research projects and published research reports on top HCI venues. Topics include online peer production platforms, data science & programming tools, STEM education, and creativity support.
- Conducted 100+ interviews & 50+ user studies; analyzed activity log of 500k+ users using statistical methods.
- Designed and built data pipelines and user-facing web applications.
- Managed teams of 5-10 researchers and engineers, set agendas, and mentored junior researchers.

#### Microsoft Research, HCI Research Intern, AI Software Development Tools

06/2022 to 09/2022

- Led a multi-phase research project on user trust in LLM-powered code generation tools; designed and conducted 30+ interviews & 20+ evaluative studies with software engineers; built visual prototypes to convey design insights.
- Generated research reports for engineering teams and disseminated findings in broader academic communities.
- Reported design insights to director-level stakeholders and GitHub Copilot product team.

#### Dataminr, HCI Research Intern, Human-AI Collaboration in NLP

09/2021 to 12/2021

- Led research on human-in-the-loop text summarization; synthesized 600+ academic literatures into design framework; developed Figma prototypes and conducted evaluative studies with crowd workers.
- Generated **research reports** for internal usage and **publications** in broader academic communities.
- Reported to director-level stakeholders and impacted the design of internal AI-powered tools.

#### Meta, UX Research Intern, Video Recommendation

06/2020 to 09/2020

- Led 20k+ surveys in 5 countries, interviews, usability tests, and statistical analysis of 20k+ user logs.
- Impacted the design of recommendation algorithms and video players with insights from international markets.
- Collaborated effectively with cross-functional teams (engineering, design, PM, and data) and vendors.

### **Education**

#### **University of Washington (UW)**

**Doctor of Philosophy** in Human Centered Design & Engineering

2023

Master of Science in Human Centered Design & Engineering

2021

University of California, San Diego (UCSD) Magna Cum Laude

Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Science (Computation) and Mathematics (Applied Science)

2018

Last Updated: February 2024